One, two! One, two, three!
I've never seen a supernova blow up.
But if it's anything
like my old Chevy Nova,
- it'll light up the night sky.
- Yeah!
Anyone who misses this will
regret it the rest of his life.
- Hey, Fry, could you go make some popcorn?
- Okay.
Let's go, microwave.
I'm in a hurry here. Hmm?
Hey.
What smells like blue?
- Fry, get up here! It's starting!
- Focus!
Hey, which crazy thing happening
are you guys screaming about?
Ooh! My popcorn's done.
Aw. It's less popped than ever.
I don't know what happened,
but we've taken on a lot of clocks.
Let's get back home.
Why is there so little traffic
around Earth?
And what's this layer of ozone?
That's never been there before.
Hmm?
- Such noises!
- Oh, no!
There's no global positioning signal.
Navigation is failing!
- We're gonna crash!
- Not if I can help it.
Oh. I guess I can't.
Everyone, put on your seat belts.
Ah, those things cost
more lives than they save.
- Bender, are you okay?
- I don't know. I'll try to move my feet.
All right, here's the plan.
Zoidberg, pick up the pieces.
Everyone else, take five.
And Zoidberg picks up another piece!
The crowd goes wild!
What is?
General, in all my years of coverin'
top secret discoveries with sheets,
I've never dramatically
revealed anything as shocking as this.
The debris from an alien spaceship.
Son, I think I can safely say...
As you can see, 1947 is going to be
an eventful year for the town of
Roswell, New Mexico.
Remarkable!
According to the high-precision
digital chronograph
it's July 9, 1947,
which would explain why
the chronograph has turned into...
- this pinup calendar.
- Wait a second.
You mean we traveled through time?
Doy! Some idiot must have
put metal in the microwave.
- Yo.
- And the microwave radiation
combined with the gravitons and graviolis
from the supernova,
blasted us through time itself.
Have you seen today's news?
"High School Gym Renovations
On Schedule"?
- What a load!
- No. Over here.
"Flying Saucer Captured."
That's no flying saucer.
- That's my ass!
- My God!
This means the flying saucer
that crashed in Roswell was us!
And the alien they captured
was... was...
- Hello.
- Ewww!
So what are you guys doing tonight?
I'm up for whatever.
Yes. We tore the universe a new
space-hole all right,
but it's clenching shut fast.
Our only hope to get back
to our own time
is to go back through it
within, oh, say
exactly 24 hours.
No problem.
The ship's fixed
except for the cup holder,
and I should have that
operational within 10 hours.
You've got eight. But a more
urgent concern is the microwave.
Without a working one, we have no hope
of returning to the future.
Well, I'm sure we can buy a microwave
somewhere around here.
Meanwhile, you guys sneak onto the army
base and rescue Bender's body.
Hey, and while we're on the base,
I'll visit my Grandfather Enos.
- He was stationed at Roswell.
- Your grandfather?
Stay away from him,
you dimwitted monkey!
You mustn't interfere
with the past.
Don't do anything
that affects anything
unless it turns out
you were supposed to do it,
in which case, for the love of God,
don't not do it!
Got it.
If, for example, you were
to kill your grandfather,
you'd cease to exist.
But existing is basically all I do!
- What is your purpose here?
- Huh?
All right, Officer.
I'll move along.
What the general means is
why did you come to Earth?
Not a day goes by
I don't ask myself the same question.
Enos!
Private, I want that toilet bowl so clean,
I could eat off it!
- 'Cause I intend to!
- Well, gadzooks, Sarge.
It's him!
It's my Grandfather Enos!
Now prepare my lunch
and place it in the latrine at 1200 hours!
That jeep's gonna hit him,
and I won't exist anymore!
Hey!
Are you crazy?
You almost got yourself run over.
I did?
Then I sure am lucky you knocked me
onto this pile of rusty bayonets.
Psst! Fry,
stop interfering with history!
I don't want to have to memorize
a lot of new kings when I get back.
I had no choice.
I was about to not exist.
I could feel myself fading away,
like Greg Kinnear.
Well, thanks, soldier.
I'm off to make Sarge's lunch.
Handlin' raw chicken?
Best part of the job.
Mmm! Finger-lickin' good.
That's it! This place is too dangerous.
We gotta get you out of here.
Everything's gonna be
all right, Dad.
Well, gadzooks!
I'd better ask Sarge.
No time! Run!
Run to safety!
This experiment will determine
what food, if any,
the alien eats.
A buffet! Oh, if only I had
my wallet with me.
Um, it's free.
Get me the president.
Fry's from around this time.
I'll talk like him.
Yo, homes!
We're looking for a microwave oven.
Microwave? Never heard
of that brand, sweetheart.
What you want is
the deluxe gas princess.
This beauty has four broilers,
a casserole indicator,
a fold-out ironing board,
and down here a foot-soaking tub
since, as a woman,
you'll be standing in front of it all day.
Oh. I'm sorry.
Now, I'll "ax" you again.
Where can we find a microwave?
Sir, your wife's hysterical,
so I'll address this to you.
This oven is lightning fast.
It takes only five hours to cook a roast.
Ooh! That's good news.
You know, you really don't cook
enough roasts, Leela.
Ohh. Women!
Oh! Thank God I got you off
that dangerous army base.
You sure are
the helpful type, stranger.
Say, you got anything to eat
in that there lunch box?
- What...
- Ooh. Snacks.
Hey, that's my brain!
Man. Them crackers
cut my mouth up somethin' bad.
Let's stop off for a malt.
- See that waitress there?
- Yowzah! I know what I want for dessert.
That's my fiancée, Mildred.
Grandma Mildred?
Uh, no dessert. Just coffee.
Okey-doke.
And for you, snuggums?
Uh, I'll have a pie
with a fried egg on top.
Yeah, she sure is pretty.
You ought to marry her and father
some children right away.
Yeah, folks say that.
But did you ever get the feeling
you're only goin' with girls
'cause you're supposed to?
What?
Don't ever, ever say
or think that again!
Please, just concentrate
on staying alive.
Fire! Look out!
You almost got neutered.
Well, 'taint as bad as gettin' killed.
For me it is!
I'm getting you out of here.
Ow!
Okay, we're in the middle of nowhere,
which is the safest part of nowhere.
Just stay put
and enjoy this calendar.
Safe and sound. Finally,
I can continue to exist.
Three, two, one.
And you are outta here!
- What'll you folks have today?
- I'll have the soylent green
with a slice of soylent orange
and some soylent coleslaw.
- Pardon?
- It's the 20th century, Professor.
Oh, right. I'll have
a croque monsieur,
the paella, two mutton pills
and a stein of mead.
I'll just have a small injection
of Fem-a-slim.
Uh, two chili dogs
comin' up.
Well, settle in. Without a microwave,
we're trapped in this time period.
Oh, Lord!
We'll have to endure
the horrible music of the Big Bopper,
and then the terrible
tragedy of his death.
Wait a second! There's a microwave
radar dish at the army base.
- We could steal it.
- No! That would alter history.
Above all else, it is our sacred duty
to preserve the past exactly as it was.
- Well, I killed my grandfather.
- Wha...
Wait. If you killed your grandfather,
why do you still exist?
I don't know.
Maybe God loves me.
Oh!
Killed? In an atomic blast?
No, sir. I'm afraid
I don't take much solace in the fact
that the implosion trigger
functioned perfectly.
Ah.
There, there. If it makes you feel any
better, his body was vaporized,
so there's no chance of him
coming back as a zombie.
- I'm not worried about that.
- Then you're a braver woman than I.
You remind me of Enos.
Would you mind walking me home?
How far is it?
Welcome to Roswell,
President Truman.
Fellas, this visit's top secret.
No one's to know about it...
except the senior officers, scientists,
and a single conspiracy nut
who no one will believe.
Mr. President, our experts
have reassembled the parts
from the alien ship
into its original design.
Hmm.
Whistlin' Dixie!
I want this sent to Area 51 for study.
But, sir, that's where
we're building the fake moon landing set.
Then we'll have to
really land on the moon.
Invent NASA and tell them
to get off their fannies!
If you come in peace,
surrender or be destroyed.
If you're here to make war,
we surrender.
Both good. The important thing is
I'm meeting new people.
Bushwah! Now, what's your mission?
Are you planning to make
some kind of alien-human hybrid?
- Are you coming on to me?
- Hot crackers! I take exception to that!
I'm not hearing a "no."
Nerts to this space crab!
If we want information,
we'll have to do us
an old-fashioned alien autopsy.
Hooray!
Every little thing
reminds me of Enos.
Aw. I know how you feel.
My grandfather died recently.
It's all so sad.
At times like this,
I just need someone to hold me.
Mmm.
You like holdin' me, don't you?
Hey, you know what
always cheers you up?
Baking me a nice tray
of sugar cookies.
How about these cookies, sugar?
I shouldn't be here.
I shouldn't even exist.
But I do exist,
which proves you can't really
be my grandm...
Mmm!
Oh, my God!
Huh?
- What the hell have you done, Fry?
- Relax.
She can't be my grandmother.
I figured it all out.
Of course she's your grandmother,
you perverted dope!
- Look!
- Come back to bed, dearie.
It's impossible!
I mean, if she's my grandmother,
who's my grandfather?
Isn't it obvious?
You are.
Did you say something, dearie?
I'm a bit hard of hearing.
Commencing excavation
of the subject's chest cavity.
And in this corner, Zoidberg!
Come on, lighten up.
What is this, a funeral?
- Heart.
- Take. I've got four of them.
one deviled egg.
Deviled egg?
The same deviled egg.
- Snap out of it!
- Start the ship, Leela.
Let's just steal the damn radar dish
and get back to our own time.
But-But won't that
change history?
Oh, a lesson in not changing history
from Mr. "I'm My Own Grandpa."
Let's get the hell out of here already!
Screw history!
U.F.O.! U.F.O.!
Hey, don't cut that.
I need that to speak.
- Oh, my...
- Great Roosevelt's ghost!
Take this, Mr. President, sir!
The president is gagging
on my gas bladder.
What an honor.
Wha...
Oh, right.
- Enos!
- He's dead! Sorry!
Choke on that, causality!
1947 can kiss my shiny metal...
Turn around!
We've gotta go back for Bender!
Impossible!
The supernova time hole is closing.
If we don't leave now,
we'll never get back to the 31st century.
Whoa!
Bender!
There. Good as new.
- Don't you need this one?
- Oh, no!
That's my...
Gotcha.
Oh. Poor Bender.
He must be so lonely right now,
trapped a thousand years in the past.
Hey, wait a second!
- Anything?
- No.
Wait!
Ow! Stupid jerk!
- He's alive!
- Whee!
Bender! What was it like lying in
that hole for a thousand years?
I was enjoying it
until you guys showed up.
Well, now everything
is back as it was.
And if history doesn't care that our
degenerate friend Fry
is his own grandfather,
then who are we to judge?
Amen!